I'm Andy Hook, a Senior UI Engineer based in Brighton.

Mobile 07980450299

Email hello@andyhook.dev

Website andyhook.dev

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/andrew-hook

Profile

Web professional with more than 10 years of experience designing and building for digital mediums. Formally educated in visual design, digital graphics and GUI. Strong design foundations and a history of collaborating closely with design teams enables me to build quality front-ends that meet the high expectations of modern users.

Skills High Performance UI

Specialist in modular design systems and component libraries for supporting fast, iterative processes within agile product teams.

- JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, Node, GraphQL, CSS3, HTML5, SVG
- React, Vue, Angular, Redux, Vuex, Nuxt, Next, RxJS, Gatsby, SSG, SSR
- Styled Components, Emotion, SCSS, LESS, Atomic, Tailwind
- Storybook, Playground, React Spring, Framer Motion, GSAP
- Babel, Rollup, Parcel, Webpack, Snowpack, Gulp

Testable, Maintainable Code

Confident code coverage enables teams to ship features faster, consistently and at a predictable cadence.

- Static type analysis, Unit, Integration and E2E testing
- Jest, Testing Library, Enzyme, Jasmine, Karma

Agile Development, UX and Accessibility

Sitting at the intersection between engineering and design allows me to act as a conduit between disciplines and speak to technical, design and product constraints during scoping and implementation.

Andy Hook
Senior UI Engineer

Experience

Senior UI Engineer

Aragon One

May 2020 - January 2021

Working with Ethereum based blockchain technologies to build censorship resistant tools for collaboration and organisation without borders. Developing, shipping and maintaining quality React interfaces for the client, upgrade and conversion tools as well as a rewards program for incentivising staking in automated liquidity pools. Driving adoption of TypeScript in front-end code, maintaining open source developer tooling.

UI Engineer

Bright Interactive

September 2018 - May 2020

Worked within an incubator team to design and build the user interface for a next-generation digital asset management product using Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, Jasmine and Karma. Supported by a backend micro-service architecture and AWS.

Senior Front-End Developer

Brandwatch

April 2016 - May 2018

UI lead within the commercial web team, worked closely with the team to overhaul the design and front-end of the core .com across multiple territories in 4+ languages.

Front-End Developer

The Jamieson Consultancy

January 2012 - January 2016

Leading creative ideation, design and development projects including the implementation of modular component libraries, from scratch site builds and campaign automation.

Digital Designer

Freelance - andyhook.dev

July 2009 - January 2012

Education

Bsc Honours Degree, Games Technology

The University of Portsmouth

September 2006 - July 2009

Foundation Diploma, Art and Design

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2005 - January 2006

National Diploma, Multimedia

Hastings College of Art and Technology

July 2003 - January 2005